<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immigration</title>
    <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Immigration</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright 2018 Hawaii J20</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 18:00:00 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Where can I get a copy of the Ho`okipa Bill passed by the Senate in 2018?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/senate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 18:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/senate/</guid>
      <description>Question: Can I get a digital copy of the Ho`okipa Bill passed by the Senate in 2018?
Background: The Ho`okipa Bill passed third reading, as amended (SD 2). In the vote on the Senate floor there were 23 ayes, Senator Kim voted aye with reservations, and Senators Gabbard and Riviere voted no. The Ho`okipa Bill was transmitted to the House of Representatives on March 6, 2018.
Answer: Here is a link to a PDF version of the Ho`okipa Bill passed by the Senate in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should taxpayers foot the bill for a sanctuary state?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/taxpayers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 18:56:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/taxpayers/</guid>
      <description>Question: Why should taxpayers bear the burden of supporting undocumented aliens?
Background: Immigration is a federal function that citizens support with the money they pay in taxes to the Internal Revenue Service. However, the federal government routinely deputizes local law enforcement agents to assist in immigration enforcement, even though the federal government does not provide funding to local governments for this purpose. This cooperation means local taxpayers effectively pay twice for immigration enforcement &amp;ndash; once with their federal taxes, and again with their state and local taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did my Representative support the Ho`okipa Bill?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/state-representatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 14:16:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/state-representatives/</guid>
      <description>Question: Did my representative support the Ho`okipa Bill during the 2018 legislative session?
Background: In the following table, the marks in the Ho`ikipa column have these meanings: ++ introduced the bill and voted aye; + voted aye; +/- voted aye with reservations; - voted nay. Note that representative names are linked to legislative web sites with contact information.
Or, view a map of House districts, where bluer indicates stronger support for the Ho`okipa bill and redder is the opposite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did my Senator support the Ho`okipa Bill?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/state-senate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 14:16:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/state-senate/</guid>
      <description>Question: Did my State Senator support the Ho`okipa Bill during the 2018 legislative session?
Background: In the following table, the marks in the Ho`ikipa column have these meanings: ++ introduced the bill and voted aye; + voted aye; +/- voted aye with reservations; - voted nay. Note that senator names are linked to legislative web sites with contact information.
Or, view a map of Senate districts, where bluer indicates stronger support for the Ho`okipa bill and redder is the opposite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should we worry about people different than us?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/waste-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 14:15:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/waste-time/</guid>
      <description>Question: Why should we waste time worrying about undocumented immigrants?
Answer: Hawai`i has a rich immigrant heritage that continues and should be allowed continue, despite any risk of losing a small amount of federal grant money. Most of us who live in Hawaii are either immigrants or the descendants of immigrants who sought better lives for themselves and their children. Immigrants have contributed significantly to our society and the unique character of Hawaii’s culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Won&#39;t a sanctuary law disrupt the flow of federal funds to Hawai`i?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/disrupt-fed-funds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 11:10:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/disrupt-fed-funds/</guid>
      <description>Question: If Hawaii refuses to cooperate with Trump and his immigration policies, he will retaliate by withholding federal grants to Hawaii. Why should Hawai`i unnecessarily put hundreds of millions of federal dollars at risk?
Background: Actually, very little federal funding would be at risk, because federal law allows grant moneys to be withheld only when a state does not comply with the requirements of that particular grant. The federal government must take care not to coerce states by withholding funds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aren&#39;t undocumented immigrants a drain on our social services?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/social-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 10:34:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/social-services/</guid>
      <description>Question: Undocumented immigrants are a drain on our communities because they get welfare and free health care, so why shouldn’t they be deported?
Background: Undocumented immigrants support government financially because they pay taxes. Yet they do not qualify for the most costly government assistance programs, such as Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid, although they may qualify for some smaller government assistance programs. Studies show that undocumented immigrants pay about as much in taxes as they receive in government programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doesn&#39;t a state sanctuary law contradict federal law?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/contradict-fed-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 10:19:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/contradict-fed-law/</guid>
      <description>Question: Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t a state sanctuary law contradict federal law?
Background: The Ho`okipa bill introduced to the Hawai`i State Legislature in 2018 does not conflict with federal law because it allows federal immigration efforts to continue. Constitutional experts agree that the provisions of the Ho`okipa bill are legal. None of its provisions have been found by any court to be in violation of federal law or the U.S. Constitution.
Similar sanctuary laws are common in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why shouldn&#39;t local law enforcement agencies assist ICE?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/assist-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 10:03:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/assist-ice/</guid>
      <description>Question: Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t local law enforcement agencies assist their law enforcement colleagues at the federal Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency (ICE)?
Background: Immigration enforcement is a federal function. Local law enforcement agencies are concerned with policing our communities. Immigration enforcement is not a function carried out by local law enforcement agencies.
When undocumented immigrants fear that local police are acting as ICE agents who can initiate deportation, they are reluctant to make contact with the police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should the state provide a safe space for undocumented immigrants?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/safe-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 09:23:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/safe-space/</guid>
      <description>Question: The Ho`okipa bill introduced to the Hawai`i State Legislature in 2018 would have provided a safe place for undocumented immigrants. Why should the State do that?
Background: The Ho`okipa bill introduced in 2018 does not provide any additional protections to undocumented immigrants than it does to citizens.
Here is its description:
 Prohibits state law enforcement agencies from complying with federal immigration detainers or honoring requests for non-public information unless specifically required to do so by a warrant signed by a judge or federal, state, or local law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hasn&#39;t the US always deported undocumented immigrants?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/always-deported/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 08:58:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/always-deported/</guid>
      <description>Question: Undocumented immigrants are deportable. Hasn&amp;rsquo;t the US always deported undocumented immigrants?
Background: The U.S. is a nation of immigrants.
For more than a century after the nation was founded in 1776, immigration was not regulated. Immigrants did not need documentation.
The federal government first began to regulate immigration in 1875, when it prohibited entry to prostitutes and criminals. At this time, the U.S. welcomed most immigrants. The Statue of Liberty, a monument to the nation&amp;rsquo;s welcoming attitude toward immigrants started construction in 1875.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why shouldn&#39;t Hawai`i comply with federal law?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/comply-with-feds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 07:43:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/comply-with-feds/</guid>
      <description>Question: The federal government is following the law in trying to remove illegal aliens. Why should the State refuse to comply with federal law?
Background: Immigration and the enforcement of immigration law is a federal function, not a state function. State and county law enforcement agents, such as the sheriff or the local police, are not legally required to enforce immigration law.
The State of Hawai`i and its counties receive no federal funds to support federal immigration programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t undocumented immigrants pose a criminal threat?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/criminal-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 07:34:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/criminal-threat/</guid>
      <description>Question: Attorney General Jeff Sessions has characterized the Chicago sanctuary law as &amp;ldquo;an official policy of protecting criminal aliens who prey on their own residents.&amp;rdquo; Along the same lines, President Trump claimed that &amp;ldquo;sanctuary cities release thousands of criminal aliens out of our prisons and jails and back into our communities. They go into those sanctuary cities when they see them. They go there because they feel they&amp;rsquo;re safe, and in many cases, they are very bad actors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is wrong with deporting undocumented aliens?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/wrong-with-deporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 07:34:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/wrong-with-deporting/</guid>
      <description>Question: Why shouldn’t undocumented immigrants be deported?
Background: Undocumented immigrants work, pay taxes, and send their children to school. Some, such as the Kona coffee farmer, Andres Magana Ortiz, are leaders in our communities. Many are married to U.S. citizens, and many of their children are U.S. citizens by birth.
Answer: The estimated 45,000 undocumented immigrants living in Hawaii are so well integrated into our communities that even their friends and neighbors may not know they are undocumented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should undocumented immigrants be allowed to stay?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/allow-to-stay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 07:04:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/allow-to-stay/</guid>
      <description>Question: Many immigrants have followed the law and are in our country legally. Why should undocumented immigrants who entered our country illegally be allowed to live here?
Background: Immigrants to the U.S. are undocumented for one of two reasons:
 They have entered our country by crossing the border without being processed, which is a misdemeanor, or They have entered our country with a visa, but have overstayed, which is a petty offense, and not a crime.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>