<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on An archaeologist reads</title>
    <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on An archaeologist reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 17:45:39 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Truth</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/on-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 17:45:39 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/on-truth/</guid>
      <description>Frank Plumpton Ramsey, who died in 1930 at the age of 26, was &amp;ldquo;an extraordinary scholarly phenomenon,&amp;rdquo; according to his editors, Nicholas Rescher and Ulrich Majer. He was appointed Cambridge University Lecturer in Mathematics at the age of 22. According to Cheryl Misak, among many accomplishments in the few short years of his career &amp;ldquo;he managed to figure out how to measure partial belief and hence lay the groundwork for decision theory and Bayesian statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Science in Archaeology</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/commons/open-science-in-archaeology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 17:45:39 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/commons/open-science-in-archaeology/</guid>
      <description>In archaeology, we are accustomed to investing great effort into collecting data from fieldwork, museum collections, and other sources, followed by detailed description, rigorous analysis, and in many cases ending with publication of our findings in short, highly concentrated reports or journal articles. Very often, these publications are all that is visible of this lengthy process, and even then, most of our journal articles are only accessible to scholars at institutions paying subscription fees to the journal publishers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wealth in old Hawai`i</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/archaeology/dye-ao-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 17:45:39 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/archaeology/dye-ao-2014/</guid>
      <description>The journals of Captain Cook and his crew contradict bad-year economic theories that posit traditional Hawaiian farmers were living at the margin. Recognising that pig herds were wealth-assets in old Hawai‘i, an alternative good-year economic theory is developed that interprets the introduction of sweet potato and the development of the rain-fed agricultural systems in which it was cultivated as processes in the creation and management of wealth. The wealth produced in this way was probably used, in part, to promote marriage alliances among elite families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Discovery of Time</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/discovery-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 15:05:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/discovery-of-time/</guid>
      <description>This seminal study of how geology and biology became historical sciences was written by the philosopher Stephen Toulmin and the historian and scientist June Goodfield. It was published by Harper &amp;amp; Row in 1965 and has been reprinted regularly since then by the University of Chicago Press.
 p. 49 Quoting Lucretius&amp;rsquo; poem On the Nature of Things: &amp;ldquo;Our age cannot look back to earlier things except where reasoning reveals their traces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>