<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Immigration</title>
    <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Immigration</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright 2018 Hawaii J20</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:31:00 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t undocumented immigrants pose a criminal threat?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/criminal-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:31:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/criminal-threat/</guid>
      <description>Question Attorney General Jeff Sessions has characterized the Chicago sanctuary law as &amp;ldquo;an official policy of protecting criminal aliens who prey on their own residents.&amp;rdquo; Along the same lines, President Trump claimed that &amp;ldquo;sanctuary cities release thousands of criminal aliens out of our prisons and jails and back into our communities. They go into those sanctuary cities when they see them. They go there because they feel they&amp;rsquo;re safe, and in many cases, they are very bad actors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is wrong with deporting undocumented aliens?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/wrong-with-deporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:32:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/wrong-with-deporting/</guid>
      <description>Question Why shouldn’t undocumented immigrants be deported?
Answer The estimated 45,000 undocumented immigrants living in Hawaii are so well integrated into our communities that even their friends and neighbors may not know they are undocumented. Undocumented immigrants work, pay taxes, and send their children to school. Some are leaders in our communities. Many are married to U.S. citizens, and many of their children are U.S. citizens by birth. Deporting undocumented immigrants would break up families and remove the main source of financial support for many minor children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should undocumented immigrants be allowed to stay?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/allow-to-stay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:32:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/allow-to-stay/</guid>
      <description>Question Many immigrants have followed the law and are in our country legally. Why should aliens who entered our country illegally be allowed to live here?
Answer Most of the undocumented immigrants who live in Hawaii have done nothing illegal arising from their immigration status. Immigrants are undocumented for one of two reasons: (1) They have entered our country by crossing the border without being processed, which is a misdemeanor, or (2) They have entered our country with a visa, but have overstayed, which is a civil offense, and not a crime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aren&#39;t undocumented immigrants a drain on our social services?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/social-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/social-services/</guid>
      <description>Question Illegal aliens are a drain on our communities because they get welfare and free health care, so why shouldn’t they be deported?
Answer Undocumented immigrants support government financially because they pay taxes. Yet they do not qualify for the most costly government assistance programs, such as Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid, although they may qualify for some smaller government assistance programs. Studies show that undocumented immigrants pay about as much in taxes as they receive in government programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doesn&#39;t a state sanctuary law contradict federal law?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/contradict-fed-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/contradict-fed-law/</guid>
      <description>Question Doesn&amp;rsquo;t a state sanctuary law contradict federal law?
Answer Hawaii’s proposed sanctuary state bill does not conflict with federal law because it allows federal immigration efforts to continue. Constitutional experts agree that the provisions of Hawaii’s proposed sanctuary state bill are legal. None of its provisions have been found by any court to be in violation of federal law or the U.S. Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hasn&#39;t the US always deported undocumented immigrants?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/always-deported/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/always-deported/</guid>
      <description>Question Undocumented immigrants are deportable. Hasn&amp;rsquo;t the US always deported undocumented immigrants?
Answer In the past, the Obama administration was responsible for deporting millions of undocumented immigrants who had committed serious crimes. However, those who had committed no serious crime were allowed to remain in the U.S. Today, Trump seeks to deport all undocumented immigrants without exception, whether they have committed a serious crime or not. The federal Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency (ICE) has recently used increasingly harsh tactics to identify and deport undocumented immigrants, including separating children from their parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should the state provide a safe space for undocumented immigrants?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/safe-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/safe-space/</guid>
      <description>Question The sanctuary state bill the State Legislature considered in the 2018 session would have provided a safe place for illegal aliens. Why should the State do that?
Answer The sanctuary bill considered in 2018 does not provide any additional protections to undocumented immigrants than it does to citizens. There is no law requiring the State or its counties to assist federal Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency (ICE), and the sanctuary state bill merely limits Hawaii’s local law enforcement agencies from assisting ICE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why should we worry about people different than us?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/waste-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/waste-time/</guid>
      <description>Question Why should we waste time worrying about undocumented immigrants?
Answer Hawai`i has a rich immigrant heritage that continues and should be allowed continue, despite any risk of losing a small amount of federal grant money. Most of us who live in Hawaii are either immigrants or the descendants of immigrants who sought better lives for themselves and their children. Immigrants have contributed significantly to our society and the unique character of Hawaii’s culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why shouldn&#39;t Hawai`i comply with federal law?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/comply-with-feds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/comply-with-feds/</guid>
      <description>Question The federal government is following the law in trying to remove illegal aliens. Why should the State refuse to comply with federal law?
Answer Hawai`i is following the law and it will continue to follow the law if it enacts a sanctuary law. Immigration and the enforcement of immigration law is purely a federal function. The State and its counties receive no federal funds to support federal immigration programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why shouldn&#39;t the state assist ICE?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/assist-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/assist-ice/</guid>
      <description>Question Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t local law enforcement agencies assist their law enforcement colleagues at the federal Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency (ICE)?
Answer Immigration enforcement is a federal function. When undocumented immigrants fear that local police are acting as ICE agents who can initiate deportation, they are reluctant to make contact with the police. They are reluctant to report crimes and suspected crimes to the police, and they are reluctant to come forth as witnesses to crimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Won&#39;t a sanctuary law disrupt the flow of federal funds to Hawai`i?</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/disrupt-fed-funds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/j20-immigration/post/disrupt-fed-funds/</guid>
      <description>Question If Hawaii refuses to cooperate with Trump and his immigration policies, he will retaliate by withholding federal grants to Hawaii. Why should Hawai`i unnecessarily put hundreds of millions of federal dollars at risk?
Answer Actually, very little federal funding would be at risk, because federal law allows grant moneys to be withheld only when a state does not comply with the requirements of that particular grant. There is only one grant related to immigration enforcement, and Hawaii receives a relatively small amount from it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>