<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on An archaeologist reads</title>
    <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on An archaeologist reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 06:48:55 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Pragmatism</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/cambridge-pragmatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 06:48:55 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/cambridge-pragmatism/</guid>
      <description>I was drawn to Cambridge Pragmatism: From Peirce and James to Ramsey and Wittgenstein by Cheryl Misak because it brings together subjective probability and C. S. Peirce&amp;rsquo;s pragmatism, two lines of thought I admire but whose relationship to one another was a mystery to me. Misak is a foremost authority on Peirce and pragmatism whose many books and articles are written with a clarity that makes them accessible to someone trained as an archaeologist, rather than a philosopher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Ages of Understanding</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/four-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 06:48:55 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/four-ages/</guid>
      <description>The subtitle of this 1,019 page book is The First Postmodern Survey of Philosophy from Ancient Times to the Turn of the Twenty-First Century. Written by John Deely, a Thomist scholar who spent 15 years translating the seventeenth century Latin work, Tractatus de Signis by John Poinsot (also known as John of St. Thomas), the Four Ages of Understanding argues that the development of the concept of sign is the central thread in the history of philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Truth</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/on-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 06:48:55 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/on-truth/</guid>
      <description>Frank Plumpton Ramsey, who died in 1930 at the age of 26, was &amp;ldquo;an extraordinary scholarly phenomenon,&amp;rdquo; according to his editors, Nicholas Rescher and Ulrich Majer. He was appointed Cambridge University Lecturer in Mathematics at the age of 22. According to Cheryl Misak, among many accomplishments in the few short years of his career &amp;ldquo;he managed to figure out how to measure partial belief and hence lay the groundwork for decision theory and Bayesian statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Discovery of Time</title>
      <link>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/discovery-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 15:05:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.tsdye.online/an-archaeologist-reads/philosophy/discovery-of-time/</guid>
      <description>This seminal study of how geology and biology became historical sciences was written by the philosopher Stephen Toulmin and the historian and scientist June Goodfield. It was published by Harper &amp;amp; Row in 1965 and has been reprinted regularly since then by the University of Chicago Press.
 p. 49 Quoting Lucretius&amp;rsquo; poem On the Nature of Things: &amp;ldquo;Our age cannot look back to earlier things except where reasoning reveals their traces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>