<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thomas S. Dye</title>
    <link>http://tsdye.online/tsdye/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thomas S. Dye</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:46:00 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tsdye.online/tsdye/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchaeoPhases</title>
      <link>http://tsdye.online/tsdye/posts/post-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:46:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tsdye.online/tsdye/posts/post-two/</guid>
      <description>In Spring 2016 I took up the opportunity to participate in a two-day conference on Bayesian statistics in archaeology in Nantes, France. Hosted jointly by Philippe Lanos of the Universit&amp;eacute; de Rennes and Anne Philippe at the Universit&amp;eacute; de Nantes, it was a chance to meet and talk with scholars actively working with Bayesian statistics, mostly as archaeologists apply those statistics to dating problems. I was able to catch up with two long-time friends, Caitlin Buck and Bo Meson from Sheffield, and had especially interesting conversations with Andrew Millard from Durham and Frances Healy from Cardiff, whose archaeological work I&amp;rsquo;d read with interest and admiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facing a new public</title>
      <link>http://tsdye.online/tsdye/posts/post-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 21:14:00 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tsdye.online/tsdye/posts/post-one/</guid>
      <description>After 17 years promoting myself as an historic preservation service provider to government agencies and private corporations, I now have the wonderful opportunity to pursue my research interests full time. This web site is my way of keeping track of what I&amp;rsquo;m doing now that my days aren&amp;rsquo;t filled completing tasks a client requires.
As a firm believer that scientific inquiry and open-source software are inseparable, I&amp;rsquo;m building my new web presence with an open-source tool chain centered on the Org mode of the Emacs editor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>